UnIon字幕組
兩周後
今天可是個大好日子
Today is best day ever.
喬遷之日
Moving Day!
誰啊
For who?
回答:波波族
Answer: The Boov.
誰是波波族啊
Who are the Boov?
回答:逃亡中的最佳種族
Answer: Best species ever at running away.
所有的波波族移民者 請到制定的運輸船報到
All Boov settlers, please report to your assigned transport.
每人限定一個手提箱
You are allowed one carry-on.
借過 抱歉
Excusing me. Sorries.
借過一下 抱歉啦哥們兒
Excusing me. Pardon the me, friend.
波波人不叫朋友
Boov do not friend.
哎呀
Owpain!
哎呀呀 對不起啦
Uh-oh. Sorries.
我是誰 我是哎呀
Who am I? I am Oh.
許許多多朋友都是這個稱呼我的
I has been given this name by my many, many friends.
- 早上好  - 哎呀
- Good morning! - Oh.
- 你們好  -
- Hi, guys. - Oh.
- 嗨嗨  - 哎呀
- Hello. - Oh.
能夠重新起步 我真是高興死了
I am very excitement to make a new fresh start!
我們就要遷移到一顆最棒的星球上去躲避啦
We are all moving to best planet ever for to hiding.
我們的新家
Our new home!
斯邁克船長
Captain Smek!
我的波波兄弟們
My fellow Boov!
我又拯救了我們一族
I has saved us again.
低一點兒
A bit lower.
不 停停
No, stop!
高一點 高一點
Up a bit. Up a bit.
很好 走開走開
Perfect. Walk away. Walk away.
我的兄弟們
My fellow--
我的
My...
兄弟們
fellow...
波波
Boov.
好消息
Good news!
多虧了我領導有方
Thanks to my leadership skills...
哆哆嗦嗦 東奔西跑 東躲西藏的
cowering, running and pulling a skedaddle...
我們終於拜託了天敵
we are safe from our enemy...
格爾族
the Gorg.
噁心吧唧
Nasty.
給爺一點掌聲
Give Daddy some sugar!
斯邁克船長再一次救了我們
Captain Smek has saved us again!
我們已經到達了銀河系最佳的藏身之處
We are now arrived at the best hiding place yet in the Milky Way.
愚蠢的船長以為Milky Way是奶油街 (⊙﹏⊙)b
格爾族們都是乳糖不耐癥
And the Gorg are lactose intolerant.
簡直天才
Genius!
他們再也找不著我們啦
They will never find us here.
謝謝大家
Thank you!
不僅如此
Best of yet...
這個星球上充滿了驚奇之物
this planet is full of great stuff.
看看這些美味的水果
Look at these delicious fruits!
讓我感覺棒棒噠
That makes me feel so good.
多有趣的派對啊
What fun at a party!
波波人不搞派對
Boov do not party.
雖然 這顆星球已經有人定居了
Also, this planet is inhabited.
但是別擔心
But do not worry.
那些土著人落後又天真
The native savages are simple and backwards.
蠢萌蠢萌的
They are so ugly, they are cute!
關於他們你們需要知道的一切
Everything you need to know about them can be found...
都在這本綜合冊子裏
in these comprehensive pamphlets.
綜合冊子 綜合冊子
Comprehensive pamphlet. Comprehensive pamphlet.
有波波族光臨 他們可幸運啊
They are lucky the Boov have come.
好啦 波波族們 入侵倒計時三秒
All right, Boov. Invade on three.
1 2 3
One, two, three.
歡呼吧 愚蠢的地球人 波波族來啦
Rejoice, humanspeople! The Boov are arrived!
現在我們要暫時的關閉你們的重力系統
Now we are turning off your gravity temporarily...
這樣能讓你們的強制遷移定居變得更容易
so as to make your mandatory relocation easier.
更有趣
And more fun!
看 是誰在飛
So, what is up?
是你們
You are!
你們抓不住我的
You'll never catch me!
好好享用你們的冰凍甜味牛軋糖
Enjoy you the frozen, sweetened bovine secretion...
此次航班目的地 人類集中營
as we take this short flight to Happy Humanstown.
好棒啊快來
This is so cool! Come on!
duang
Fa-da!
人類在人類集中營裏從此過上了幸福快樂的生活
Humanspersons are happiness and joy forever in Happy Humanstown.
歡迎搬進新家
Welcome to your new home.
- 什麼啊 等一等  - 新家
- Wait, what? No! - New home?
餘下的星球都歸波波人啦
And rest of planet is for Boov.
雙贏
Win-win!
歡迎你們 波波殖民者
Welcome, Boov settlers.
所有的人類都被遷移了
All humans have been relocated.
你們的新家正等著你們呢
Your homes are now ready.
多謝了您吶
Thanking you!
這星球還需要一些修修補補
This planet may be a bit of a fixing-it-upper...
但還好啦
but that is okay.
波波人很擅長區分什麼是精華
Boov are best at deciding what is useful.
什麼是糟粕
And what is not.
哎呀
Owpain.
靠邊站 我是清理員
Step aside. Clean-up crew.
沒用
Useless.
今日 是我的新生
Today, I starts a new life.
新的朋友 新的家園
With new friends. In a new home.
居民請進入179號區域
Residents may now enter sector 179.
那是我
That is me!
這就是為什麼今天那麼美好
And that is why today is best day ever!
歡迎回家 好鄰居
Welcome home, neighbors!
波波人沒有鄰居
Boov do not have "neighbors."
這是因為之前星球的大小和地貌
That is owing to the size and topography of our former planet.
喂 借我一點糖好不好啊
Hey! Can I borrowing a cup of sugar?
你在說什麼
What?
可如今 近在咫尺的鄰里可融洽多啦
But now, our closer proximity can leads to friendship.
我邀請你們所有人
You are all invited...
參加我的新居喬遷宴
to my warming of house party.
5點怎麼樣
Say, 5:00?
好
Sure.
棒
Yes!
喂 豬豬 小心
Hey, Pig! Be careful up there!
抱歉啦 豬豬
I'm sorry, Pig.
媽媽不在這裏
Mom's not here.
就是個視頻而已
It's just a video.
媽媽 我覺得豬豬想跟我們一起玩
Hey, Mom. I think Pig wants to join us.
有什麼好笑的啦
It's not funny!
小蒂
Tip!
行啦 媽媽 就是點雪而已
Come on, Mom. It's just snow.
我可不懂什麼雪
I don't know anything about snow.
我們來自巴巴多斯 那兒可不下雪
We're from Barbados! We don't have snow!
你還好吧
Are you okay?
我要讓所有人都看到這個
I'm sending this to everyone.
195號區域可供入住
Sector 195 is ready for occupation.
我們不能再等下去了 豬豬 我們走
We can't wait for Mom, Pig. We gotta go.
立刻
Right now!
不
Oh, no!
準備施展你的舞步
Prepare for your dance attack!
好吧 我們去找媽媽
Okay, let's go find Mom.
好鄰居們 你們好
Neighbors, hello!
請進
Please come in and--
有人嗎
Hello.
Hello?
好吧 左轉 再左轉
And right. And left. Other left.
凱爾
Kyle!
右 不對 左
Right. No, left.
你好 凱爾好友
Hello, friend Kyle.
我不是朋友
I am not your friend.
你當然是 我們的談話可愉快了
Of course you are. We have had many enjoyable talks.
我們說話只是因為我沒法走開
No, we talk only because I'm not allowed to move.
你總是說有勁的事情
You are always saying the funny things.
也許今晚你能來我的新居喬遷宴
Perhaps you can say them at my warming of house party tonight.
我不去 派對毫無益處 還浪費寶貴的波波時間
I will not. Parties are useless and take up valuable Boov time.
既然你在忙 我就給你發電子邀請函吧
Since you are at your busyness, I shall send an e-vite to you...
你有空了就來參加吧
so you can join later during your leisure minute.
求別發 我很珍惜我的空閒時間
Please do not send. I enjoy my leisure minute.
duang 我已經發送了我家的坐標
Fa-da! I have sent directions to my living space.
你給所有人都發了坐標
You sent directions to everyone?
什麼 這可不是我的錯
What? It is not my fault.
你為什麼要把發送鍵放在群發送旁邊
Why for put "send" button right next to "send all"?
這可是不良設計
This is just bad design.
你的邀請函已經發送個全星系了
Your invite has been sent to entire galaxy!
哎呀
Uh-oh.
哎呀個鬼啊
"Uh-oh" is right!
我們的敵人 格爾族 也會收到的
Our enemy, the Gorg, will receive it...
他們能通過坐標找到我們
and can use directions for to find us!
格爾族
The Gorg?
duang
Fa-da!
我們一族要玩完啦
You have doomed our species!
不 求求你們
No, please.
我不是故意的 我錯了
I did not mean to. I am sorries!
你被逮捕了
You are arresting!
不
No!
我只是想邀請你們
I was just trying to invite you to my--
安保系統被破壞了
Security has been compromised.
逮捕他
Arrest that Boov!
自動駕駛 我需要幫助
Autopilot, I needs help!
位於巴黎的波波總部可以提供幫助
Help is available in Paris at Boov Headquarters.
不 自動駕駛 絕對不去巴黎
No, Autopilot! Any place but Paris!
你必須帶我去一個沒有波波族的地方
You must takes me to a place with no Boovs.
唯一沒有波波族居住的地方是南極洲
The only remaining spot on planet with no Boov is Antarctica.
大擁抱
Group hug!
好啊 南極洲棒極了 帶我去吧
Yes! Antarctica is perfect! Take me there now!
抱歉你是逃亡中的波波人
I am sorry. You are fugitive Boov.
啟動自毀模式
Initiating Self-Destruct.
不 不要啟動
No! Do not initiate!
我不是逃亡者
I am not a fugitive!
不
No!
Oh, no.
抓住你了 抓住你了
Gotcha, gotcha, gotcha!
你幹嘛這麼做
What for are you did this?
我是波波人 萬眾敬仰的波波人
I am Boov, beloved by all humans.
我知道你是誰
I know what you are.
好極了 放我出來吧
Excellent! Can I come into the out now?
不行 你不准出來
No, you cannot "come into the out" now.
你再也出不來了 別想了
You can never come into the out, ever again!
這可不行
But I can!
你得把木棍拿走不可
You are just having to take away the piece of wood.
不然我就要
Then I will have to--
釋放破壞死光了
I will shoot forth the lasers from my eyeballs!
你做得到嗎
You can do that?
是的
Yes.
要是你真的那麼做了 那我別無選擇
If you shoot your eye lasers, then I'll have no choice...
只好炸掉你的腦袋了
but to explode your head!
- 你們人類沒法只在爆炸的  - 當然能
- You humans cannot to explode-- - We can too!
只是不太那麼做
We just don't much.
那樣太粗魯
It's considered rude.
那我提出休戰
Then I am granting you a truce.
你別炸開我的頭
You are not to exploding heads...
我也不放激光了
and I will not do my devastating eye lasers.
好的 休戰
Okay. Truce.
- 那麼 放我出來吧  - 不
- So, can I come into the out now? - No!
這是懲罰你們搶了這顆星球 劫持了人們
This is what you get for stealing planets and abducting people.
你想錯了
You are thinking a mistake.
波波人既不偷搶 也不劫持
Boov do not steal and abduct.
波波人自由又友好
No, Boov liberate and befriend.
猜猜這是誰做的
Guess who made this one!
這個好漂亮
This is so beautiful!
媽媽 這是怎麼了
Mom! What's happening?
我不知道 寶貝
I don't know, honey.
小蒂
Tip!
我沒事的
It will be okay.
偵測到生命形式 非人類 不予理睬
Lifeform detected. Not human. Move along.
享受你們的冰凍牛扎軟糖
Enjoy you the frozen, sweetened bovine secretion...
此次航班終點站 人類集中營
as we take this short flight to Happy Humanstown.
媽媽
Mom!
全都是你的錯
It's all your fault.
你偷走了我媽媽
You stole my mom!
再見 波波
Smell ya later, Boov.
等等 現在就見
Wait! Smell me now!
我可以幫你修車 我看到你的車撞壞了
I can to fixing your car. I seen you has broken it.
我沒撞壞 我可是個好司機
I didn't break it. I'm a very good driver.
它本來就是這樣的
It's supposed to leak like that.
我現在能出來了嗎
Can I come into the out now?
我知道 那個逃亡的波波人已經犯下了一系列大錯
I know the fugitive Boov has made yet another in a series of horrible...
卻是無意的逗比錯誤
yet unintentionally humorous mistakes.
我想你們保證 他發送的信號
But let me reassure you, the signal he broadcast...
已經被搞定了
is being handled.
我們不會滅絕的
We are definitely not doomed.
- 我們沒事了  - 我們死定了
- And we're out. - We are doomed!
格爾族會再次找到我們的
The Gorg are going to find us again!
那個瘋子波波搞砸了一切
The maniac Boov has ruined everything.
糟透了
This is bad.
我可愛這顆星球了
And I really love this planet.
看看這些了不起的東西
Look at all the great stuff they've got.
比如這個 髮箍
Like this! A headband!
你還可以穿在上身 向下滑
And for evening wear, you slide it down...
就有了一個備用輪胎
you got a beautiful spare tire.
我好喜歡
I love it!
真漂亮
Very nice!
誰願意拋下這一切 我非得搞定不可
Who would wanna leave this behind? I have got to fix this.
我知道
I know!
召喚大腦波波
Summon the Big Brain Boovs.
自作聰明的智商達人
The smarty-pants of all smarty panty Booviness.
神十波
Gentleboov...
我需要主意
I want ideas.
我們可以創造一個沒有格爾族的替換現實
We could create an alternate reality with no Gorg in it...
然後住到那兒去
then go live there.
好耶 我喜歡
Yes! I love it!
這麼做需要多久
How long would that take?
基於目前的科技
Based on our current technology...
1700萬年
1.7 million years.
這可太久啦 托尼 換別的
That's a lot of years, Toni. Moving on!
- 我們可以就地躺下  - 好的
- We could lay on the ground... - Yes!
讓格爾族以為我們都死了
and make the Gorg think we are dead.
下一個
Next!
我們幹嘛不登陸逃亡波波的電郵
What if we logged into the fugitive Boov's email...
然後取消他的電子邀請
and cancelled his e-vite--
噓噓 或者我們登陸逃亡者的電郵賬號
Shush! Or we could log into the fugitive Boov's email...
取消邀請
and cancel his invitation, and...
然後怎麼著
What was that?
格爾族絕不會收到邀請
So the Gorg never receive it.
So the Gorg never receive it!
現在輸入密碼 取消信息
Now, type in the password and cancel that message.
把密碼設成"密碼"真是個好主意啊
It was a good idea of me to make all passwords "password."
容易記憶
It's so easy to remember.
沒有用 他的密碼太獨特
It did not work! His password is unique.
不
No!
獨特 波波人不獨特
Unique? Boov are not unique!
把我的充氣機取來
Fetch me my inhaler.
小子們 這會奏效的
Boy, that works.
他的錯誤會直接把格爾族引過來
His mistaking is leading the Gorg right to us.
讓我看看他的請帖
Show me his invite.
你們都收到我的派對邀請啦
You are all invited to a party!
只要去銀河系
Just head to the Milky Way.
在北斗星的地方右拐
Turn right at the Big Dipper.
太陽系的第三顆行星
Third planet from the Sun.
看看我的氣球 派對
Look for my balloons! Party!
想要玩的痛快就來吧
Come if you like to have fun!
我最好的朋友凱爾也回會來的
My best friend Kyle will be there!
凱爾 凱爾 凱爾
Kyle, Kyle, Kyle!
來聚會吧
Come party!
凱爾
Kyle!
他不是我的朋友
He is not my friend.
互聯網不會撒謊
The internet does not lie!
你瞭解他 你能找到他
You know him, you can find him.
我交給你負責了
I am putting you in charge!
可是 船長 這不是的我的工作 我只是個中級交通協管員波波
But, Captain, it is not my job. I am only a mid-level traffic Boov.
- 我欣賞你的懦弱 長官  - 謝謝
- I admire your cowardice, Officer. - Thank you.
我要每一個斯邁克之地星球上的波波警察搜索整個城市
But I want every Boovcop on Planet Smekland searching this city.
我們需要他的密碼
We need his password...
不然就等著被格爾族消滅吧
or we will all be destroyed by the Gorg!
找到他
Find him!
那個波波已經病入膏肓了
That Boov has made his final mistake.
duang
Fa-da!
你不是說要修好它的嗎
You were supposed to fix it!
這是什麼玩意兒
What is this?
我管它叫"爛泥怪"
I calls it "Slushious."
"爛泥怪"
"Slushious"?
它有無與倫比的燃料
It makes excellent fuel...
噴出新奇搞笑的味道
and comes in fun-to-say flavors.
"甜葡萄"
"Grape Escape."
"柑橘卷"
"Tangerine Twist."
"酸青檸"
"Busta Lime"!
媽媽要弄死我了
Mom's gonna kill me.
現在 我準備接受你們地球人表達感激的手勢了
Now I am prepared to accept one of your traditional gestures of human gratitude.
事實上 我們的傳統是給你一頓皮蛋大餐 站著別動
Actually, our tradition is to punch you in the nose. Hold still.
不 你一點都不感激
No! Your gratitude is implied.
你要先開車了
You can drives first.
之後我就能…
Then I can...
你不能跟來
You're not coming.
我正想要去躲避波波族 我才不會帶上一個跟著我
I'm trying to hide from the Boov. I'm not bringing one with me.
你正好就能把我告發了
You'll just turn me in.
不 我僅僅需要一個交通工具
No! I just needs a ride!
在鎮上我有一個波波族的官方任務要解決
I haves official Boov business out of in town.
我也是
Me, too.
但是我改進了你的汽車
But I fixes your car!
所以呢 我把你從冰箱裏救了出來 我們扯平了
So? I let you out of the freezer. We're even.
- 你對我的車做了什麼  - 你還想要哪樣的操作系統
- What did you do to my car? - What doos you mean?
它現在應該能更好的在空中懸浮了
It should to hover much better now.
它只是輛車 它以前從來沒在空中懸浮過
It's a car. It didn't hover at all before.
你怎麼能讓這東西停下
How do you stop this thing?
誒呦 很顯然 我把油門和剎車弄反了
Oops. I have apparently reversing the proceed and anti-proceed controls.
是的 我明白了 剎車是油門
Yeah, I noticed. Stop is go.
- 油門是剎車  - 等下
- Go is stop. - Wait!
你為什麼要這麼做 波波和人類是朋友
Whyfor you do this? Boovs and humans are friends!
我們不是朋友 你們綁架了我媽媽
We're not friends. You kidnapped my mom!
誰是邁瑪
Who is Mimom?
我剛才說的是什麼
What did I say?
- 我知道如何找到她  - 如何
- I knows how to find her. - How?
你媽媽的信息在中央司令部
That information is at Boov Central Command.
- 在天線之末  - 什麼
- At the Great Antenna. - What?
在巴黎 現在讓我進去
In Paris! Now let me to inside!
巴黎
Paris.
- 那麼承諾  - 什麼
- Then promise. - What?
承諾你會幫助我找到她 否則我就把你扔在這裏
Promise you'll help me find her or I'm leaving your Boov butt.
我承諾 但是如果你不希望被抓 現在就跑
I promise! But if you do not wish to be capturing, it must be now!
好吧 進來
Fine. Get in.
沒錯 沒錯 豬豬 巴黎 我們來了
Oui, oui, Pig! Paris, here we come.
我們要查明他們把媽媽關在哪裏
We're gonna find out where they put Mom.
好 我要設定GPS讓我們直線飛去巴黎
Okay. I shall set the GPS to take us straight to the Paris.
目的地 南極
Destination entered: Antarctica.
嘿 你在做什麼
Hey, what are you doing?
怎麼會這樣
How did that happen?
把你的外星爪子從我的車上拿開
Keep your Boov paws off my car!
喔
Whoa!
你的車上全是害蟲
Your vehicle is infested.
它不是害蟲 他是我的寵物
It's not infested. He's my pet.
他叫豬豬 別碰他
His name is Pig. Don't touch him.
現在他在晃
Now he is vibrating.
難道他要爆炸了
Is he going to explode?
不 他只是在打呼嚕
No! He's just purring.
你為什麼要養這種東西
Why do you haves this thing?
它有用麼 他能生產肉或者牛奶嗎
Is it useful? Does it give meat or milk?
什麼 不
What? No!
你養寵物只是為了快樂和友誼
You just have pets for fun and companionship.
在這艘船上你有我當你的同伴
You has me for companion on the ship.
是 好吧 豬豬更好一些
Yeah, well, Pig is better.
如果貓叫做豬豬 那你叫什麼
If cat is "Pig," what is your name?
格拉托依蒂·圖琪 但是我朋友都叫我小蒂
Gratuity Tucci. But my friends call me "Tip."
- 小蒂  -我說了」我朋友」
- Tip. - I said "my friends."
但我們就是朋友 所有的人類和波波都是
But we are friends. All humans and Boov.
斯邁克船長船長決定的
Captain Smek has decided.
斯邁克船長船長是個傻瓜
Captain Smek is an idiot.
錯
Untrue!
斯邁克船長是個天才和逃跑大師
Captain Smek is genius and best at running away.
難道你沒聽說過關於噓噓的傳說嗎
Have you not heard the legend of the Shusher?
很久以前 我們的敵軍 格爾族
Long ago, our enemy, the Gorg...
邀請波波族參加一個和平會談
invited the Boov to a peace meeting.
但是斯邁克船長在恐懼中明智的逃走了
But Smek wisely fled in terror.
然後他得到了一個特殊的戰利品 噓噓
And he took a great trophy: the Shusher.
跑啊
Run away!
為什麼要叫它噓噓
Why is it called the "Shusher"?
噓噓
Shush!
隨便吧
Whatever.
真的嗎
Seriously?
你們這些傢伙破壞了自由女神像
You guys had to ruin the Statue Of Liberty?
斯邁克雕像
"Statue of Smek."
你們會因此受到懲罰
You will not get away with this.
波波巡邏隊
Boov Patrol!
他們正在找你
They are looking for you!
哦 不
Oh, no.
Oh, no!
這是什麼
What's that?
嘿
Hey!
不要讓司機分心
Don't distract the driver!
哈哈 巴斯塔酸橙汁
Aha! Busta Lime.
「巴斯塔酸橙汁」
"Busta Lime."
好痛
Owpain!
Owpain.
好的 尿尿時間
Okay. Pee break.
我也要去尿尿
I, too, has to break pee.
或者按你這麼叫的 一號
Or, as you calls it, the "number one."
- 我們也有二號  - 好吧
- We also has the "number two." - Okay.
- 然後是三號  - 好吧
- And the "number three." - Okay!
我不必去上3號對你來說是件好事
It is a good thing I doos not have to go the number three.
他會讓你處境危險
It would not be safe for you.
我們一年就上一次三號
We only doos it once a year.
我不會把它叫做假期
I would not call it a holiday...
- 但是你上三號需要花上一天  - 夠了
- but you doos need to take the day off. - That's enough!
你不能進來 這是女廁所
You can't come in here. This is the girls' room.
不要吃那個藍色的薄荷糖
Do not eat the blue mints!
感謝上帝 這有一大碗檸檬水
Thankfully, there is a large bowl of lemonade.
不要喝檸檬水
Do not drink the lemonade!
馬上就出來了
Be out in a second.
我們要去巴黎
We're going to Paris!
去見媽媽
Going to see my mom!
慢慢享受
Takes your time!
南極
Ant-arc-tica.
我來了
Here I come!
逃亡的波波
Fugitive Boov.
別動 我逮捕你了
Hold still for arresting!
我最好的朋友 凱爾
Best friend Kyle!
我不是你的朋友
I am not your friend!
但我會得到你的密碼 成為一名英雄波波
But I will be a hero Boov for getting your password.
好 你在千鈞一髮之際救了我們
Yes! You has in nick-time saved us!
你這表情是什麼意思
What is the purpose of your face?
好痛
Owpain.
你想要丟下我
You were gonna ditch me?
- 不  - 騙子
- No! - Liar!
我從不說謊
I never lie!
你說了
Yes, you do!
你知道 我是怎麼知道的嗎
And you know how I know?
因為每當你說謊的時候 你就會變綠
Because every time you lie, you turn green!
我沒有 我...
I doos not. I...
拆穿了
Poomp.
開門 騙子 長著一張青蛙臉的濕玩具
Open the door, you lying, frog-faced squishy toy!
停 我需要你...
Stop! I need your...
你承諾過要幫我找到我媽媽
You promised to help me find my mom!
然後我要違背承諾
Then I un-promise!
不能這樣
That's not how it works!
你必須幫我去巴黎
You have to help me get to Paris.
我不幫
I will not!
停 我需要你...
Stop! I need your...
我必須藏起來
I must hide!
我也說的英語 你為什麼就不明白呢
I am speaking the English at you. Whyfor do you not understands me?
我理解 我只是不在乎而已
I "understands." I just don't care.
- 別動  - 當心
- Freezing! - Look out!
不要
Come on!
停 我需要你的密碼
Stop! I need your password.
不
No!
跑
Go!
我就是想要個密碼
All I wanted was his password.
這並不是一個能忍受的友誼方式
This is not a sustainable friendship model.
所以...
So...
我假設現在我們已經逮捕了亡命大盜
I assume by now we have apprehended the fugitive.
有人嗎
Anybody?
你 紫色的那個
You. The purple one.
不是這個紫色的 是另一個紫色的 另一個
Not that purple. The other purple. The other purple.
那個
That one.
對 就是你
Yes, you!
所以 他在哪
So, where is he?
我們不知道 先生
We do not know, sir.
什麼 這是第一名的災難
What? This is number one disaster!
他的郵件可千萬不能被格爾族看到
His message must not reach the Gorg.
這個星球可是千辛萬苦找到的 我絕不放棄它
This planet was hard to find, and I will not abandon it!
把我的壓力釋放泡泡墊拿來
Someone fetch me my stress blankie.
太爽了
So soothing.
凱爾警長來啦
Aha! Officer Kyle!
總算來了一個盡職盡責的波波人
Now here is a Boov who knows how to do his job.
你一定會告訴我找到逃犯了對不對
Tell me, you have found the fugitive?
是的
Yes.
這絕對是普天同慶的歷史時刻
Joyful exclamation!
他在哪兒勒
And where is he?
發生了一丟丟的問題
There is a tiny problem.
既然只是 "一丟丟" 那誰還在乎呢
"Tiny." As long as it's tiny, who cares?
就在我獲得密碼之前
Well, before I got the password...
他溜了
I erased him.
來晚會吧 來晚會吧 來晚會吧
Come party. Come party. Come party.
- 輕點啊  - 對不起啦
- Quit it! - Sorry.
聽著 對你我來說巴黎很危險
Look, Paris is danger for both of us.
那裏到處都是波波人
It crawls with Boov.
我們到了那兒之後你有什麼計劃
Doos you have a plan for once we are get there?
暫時沒想好 但我還是有勝算的
Not really. But I have hope.
你數學是體育老師教的嗎
You are bad at math.
你說什麼
Excuse me?
我幾何學可是拿過 "A" 的好嗎
I got an "A" in geometry.
我的意思是
I am only saying...
波波族在數學上的造詣是你們不能比的
Boov are superior in this way.
只要勝算低於50%
If probability for success falls below 50%...
波波族就放棄 你們就不會
Boov give up. You do not.
確實如此
Exactly!
不要再撕了
Enough with the ripping!
好的 好的
Okay, okay.
要不這樣吧 我們聽聽音樂
Tell you what. Let's have some tuneage.
那是什麼
What is that?
波波樂
Boov song.
歌名叫 "靜止與服從"
It is called "Motionless and Obedient."
超流行的單曲
Very big hit.
不不不 在我的車裏不允許放這種音樂
No, no, no! Not in my car.
司機才有選擇權
Driver gets to pick.
這甚至都不能稱之為音樂好嗎 這是噪音
This is not even music. This is just noise.
這種身體反應絕非我意
Involuntary physical response.
你騙我
You have tricked me
聽這種聲波武器讓我變得虛弱
into listening to a debilitating sonic weapon.
如果你想讓人類不討厭你的話
If you want humans to not hate you...
那你可以從喜歡我們人類的事物開始做起
you could start by liking some of our stuff.
這太奇怪了 我的身體是怎麼了
Confusion. What is happening to my body?
這叫跳舞
It's called dancing!
波波族才不會跳舞呢
Boov do not dancing!
我看出來啦 但你技巧掌握得還蠻快的嘛
I can tell. But you're getting the hang of it!
我要被它折磨瘋了
How long before this kills me?
我完全不能控制我的須須們了
I am not in control of my own extremities!
就是這樣 動起來
That's it. Work it!
我不想動哇
I do not want it to work!
你知道嗎
You know what?
"波波" 和 "樂樂" 押韻
"Boov" rhymes with "groove."
搖擺搖擺 快樂搖擺
Shake your Boov thang.
我的屁屁搖擺得不甚優雅啊
It is shaking in a most undignified way!
哦不 我的手在飛舞 就像我不在乎
Oh, no! My hands are in the air like I just do not care!
這不應該是波波人應有的表現啊
This is not how a Boov behaves!
羞恥感讓我渾身發燙
I am overheated with shame!
- 我必須冷卻一下  - 等等
- I must cool my core! - Wait!
- 你在做什麼  - 我會回來的
- What are you doing? - I will returning!
我們正玩兒得開心呢
We were having fun!
快來 媽媽 只是雪而已啦
Come on, Mom. It's just snow!
我從來沒有見過雪
I don't know anything about snow.
這是我們的第一場雪
Our first snow!
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
我要把這寄給
I'm sending this to--
我的體溫已恢復到快樂的水平
My temperature is back to happiness.
為了表示我對你沒有任何的不滿
And to show I do not hold against you any grudge-ment...
我給你帶來了可口的點心
I have brought you delicious snacking.
看 有嚼勁的塑料環
Fa-da! Chewy plastic rings!
我真心不喜歡你們人類的感謝方式
I really do not enjoy your human gratitude customs.
你去哪兒了
Where have you been?
你就那麼永遠得走掉了
You were gone forever!
這句話並不準確 "永遠" 指的是
That is not accurate. "Forever" is--
我還以為你死了或者受傷了
I thought you were dead! Or hurt!
或者遇到其他什麼事
Or I don't know!
你絕不可以像這樣把一個人單獨留下
But you cannot just leave someone alone like that!
把腳放在我的鞋子裏
Put yourself in my shoes!
我怎麼可能穿你的鞋子
How could I wears your shoes?
我的腳太小了
My pods are too small.
這只是一種措辭
It's an expression!
意思是你要設身處地為別人著想
It means try to feel how someone else feels.
我還只是個孩子
I'm just a kid.
我不應該總是自己承擔一切
I'm not supposed to be by myself all the time.
這簡直就是孩子的危機 同時也是一種犯罪
This is child endangerment. Which is a crime, by the way.
但是我見到你的時候你就已經是一個人了呀
But when I founded you, you were already alone...
所以我以為對你來說這很正常
so I thinks it is normal for you.
小波波們都是在恆溫爐裏養大的
When Boov are young, we are kept in the warming oven.
這對人類來說正常嗎
Is this normal for humanspersons?
通常
Usually
我們只有滿了16歲才會獨自橫跨大西洋
We don't cross the Atlantic by ourselves until we're 16.
不 發生的這些事都不正常
No, none of this is normal!
你還沒明白嗎 你毀了一切
Don't you get it? You ruined everything!
本來我終於在這兒找到了快樂
I was finally happy here-- there, where I lived.
和媽媽一起居住的地方
With my mom.
你知道對我來說適應有多困難
Do you know how hard it was for me to fit in?
我用了多久才習慣
How long that took?
七年級的女生都不好惹
7th-grade girls are mean!
是 我發現了 我之前都沒意識到
Yes, I sees that! I did not realize!
我們會重新找邁瑪的
We will resume the finding of Mimom.
別再這麼說了好嗎
Stop saying that!
她是我的媽媽
She's just "my" mom.
不是你的 是我的
Not yours. Mine.
你為什麼就是搞不清楚呢
How do you not understand this?
如果長相怪異的外星人
How would you feel
把你媽媽從你身邊帶走 你會做何感想
if some horrible aliens took your mother from you?
這不可能發生
That could not to happen.
波波人沒有邁瑪
Boov are not having mimoms.
原來你們沒有家人
Boov don't have families.
怪不得你們搶奪別人的東西而且一點也不在乎別人的感受
No wonder you take things and don't care about anybody else.
所以說 你的邁瑪
So, your mimom...
對你來說非常重要
is a very important humansperson to you.
比任何人都重要
More important than others.
不能和她在一起的話 你就會傷心
To not belong with her causes you being sad.
但是剛剛你還在對我拳打腳踢 衝我叫喊
But recent moments ago, you are kicking on me and yelling.
看起來不是傷心 而是生氣
Which is seeming more to be mad than sad.
有時兩者皆有
Well, sometimes it's both.
所以你是傷心地生氣
So, you are sad-mad.
原來人類比書上說的複雜得多
Humans are more complicated than it said in the pamphlet.
我盡快地把這兒用吸塵器打掃乾淨了
I vacuumed here as fast as I could.
你們對
Whatfor is your plan
破解密碼有了什麼想法
for figuring out the dumb Boov's password?
我沒什麼收穫
I got nothing!
拜託 我需要大家的想法
Please, come on! I need ideas!
就是你 紫色的那個
You! The purple one.
拜託
Oh, come on!
所以勒
So?
也許我們可以隨機地輸入數字和字母
We could type in random numbers and letters?
贊
I like it!
超級大腦們快快連接工作起來
Get those big brains plugged in and working.
走著
Away!
你們知道一旦格爾人發現我們 下場會怎樣
You know what the Gorg will do if they find us.
喀嚓 喀嚓 喀嚓
Chomp, chomp, chomp.
所以我們才要一直逃亡
And that is why we keep running away.
哇噢
Whoa.
為什麼格爾族那麼恨你們
Why do these Gorg hate you so much?
因為他們是格爾人啊
Because they are Gorg.
我們稱他們為 "掠奪者"
We calls Gorg the "takers"...
因為你有什麼 他們就搶什麼
because if you has something, they takes it.
比如你有一塊三明治
Like, if you has a sandwich.
或一個星球
Or a planet.
好啦 好啦 我理解了
No, no. I get it.
但他們不會來地球 對吧
But they're not coming to this planet, right?
不不 這倒不用擔心
Oh, no, no. Not to worry.
超級大腦波波人會彌補我的失誤的
The Big Brain Boov will to fix my mistake.
但我還是會被處罰得很慘
But I will still be very punished.
我們有項規定
We has a rule.
違規九次即出局
Nine mistakes and you are out.
那你犯規了幾次
How many mistakes do you have?
62次
62.
我情緒低落的時候 媽媽就會給我講笑話
When I'm stressed out, my mom tells me jokes.
波波人不會講笑話
Boov do not do telling jokes.
沒那麼難 我來教你吧
It's not that hard. I'll teach you.
咚 咚
Knock, knock.
你應該說  " 門外是誰 「
You would say, "Who's there?"
是你
You are there.
不 你只要問我就好了
No, just ask me.
門外是誰
Who is there?
現在我說  "打斷牛」
Now I say, "The interrupting cow."
現在你說  "誰是打斷牛 「
Now you say, "The interrupting cow, who?"
我們開始吧
Let's just do it.
- 咚 咚   - 門外是誰
- Knock, knock. - Who is there?
打斷牛
The interrupting cow.
- 打斷牛  - 哞
- The interrupting cow-- - Moo!
我還沒問你呢
You did not let me finish my response.
- 我剛才應該說 "哪個打斷-- "  -哞
- I was to say, "The interrupting co--" - Moo!
你又那麼干
You did it again.
這是個玩笑
That is the joke.
這隻牛是打斷牛
The cow is to being an interrupting cow...
所以在我說話時打斷了
and therefore interrupts me!
- 我知道 這就是它有趣的地方  - 哞
- I know. That's why it's funny. - Moo!
-讓我說--  -哞
- Let me fi-- - Moo!
-夠了  - 我是打斷牛
- That's enough. - I'm the interrupting cow.
- 住口  - 哞
- Knock it off! - Moo!
-別逼我用膠帶封上你的嘴啊  -哞
- Don't make me get out more tape! - Moo!
好多波波啊
So many Boovs!
我說過這太傻了
I said this was dumbness.
我說過我是命中注定的 但是你聽了嗎 沒有
I said I am doomed. But doos you listen? No!
夠了
Oh, that's enough!
你快把我逼瘋了
You are driving me to the crazy!
現在跑還不晚 那是波波族的格言
It is never too late to run away. That is the Boov motto.
是的 但是我們不會逃跑 我有一個計劃
Yes, but we're not doing that. I have a plan.
你的計劃是逃跑嗎 如果不是 那都是蠢方法
Is your plan to run away? Because other-way-wise, it is stupid!
我們需要做的就是潛入這個城市
All we have to do is sneak into the city...
進入偉大的天線 利用它來找到我媽媽
get into the Great Antenna, use it to find my mom...
然後再偷偷溜走 明白了嗎
and then sneak out again. See?
但是這樣還是行不通呀 因為他們認識我
But it still will not work because my face is known.
如果我被任何一個波波看到
If I am seen by any Boov,
我百分之百會被抓起來的
I am 100% popular for being arrested.
如果我有辦法呢
What if I could fix that?
別動
Hold still.
首先 一個小雀斑
First, a little beauty mark.
讓我看看
Letting me see.
-還沒好呢 把鏡子給我  - 給我 給我
- Not yet. Give me that mirror. - Give to me, give to me!
這看起來完全不像我了
It is like looking at a completed stranger!
不 我還沒完成呢 甚至還沒有--
No, I'm not done. It's not even--
你真是個魔術師
You are a worker of miraculous transformation!
這個波波是誰
Who is this Boov?
我不認識
I do not know!
好吧 哇哦
All right, Oh.
好痛
Owpain.
電梯離開
Express elevator departing.
哇哦
Whoa!
這太令人興奮了
This is uber freaky
這些都是最聰明的波波嗎
These are the smartest Boov you have?
你一定要安靜
You must be very quiet.
你肯定不想打破他們集中--
You do not want to break their concentra--
派對開始啦 派對開始啦
Come party. Come party.
哦 這是什麼
Oh! What is it?
我想現在大腦袋波波已經停止了
I thought the Big Brain Boovs would have stopped my invitation by now.
但是他們還沒有找到我的密碼
But they have still not figured out my password.
- 這可能嗎  - 等一下
- How is this possible? - Wait a minute.
這是說這些可怕的格爾族惡魔
Does this mean those horrible monster Gorg thingies
將要去地球了嗎
will come to Earth?
去地球 是的
To Smekland, yes!
然後會發生什麼
And what happens then?
再也不會找到邁瑪了
There will be no finding of Mimom!
你要解決這個問題
Then you've gotta fix this!
好
Yes.
快點
Hurry!
順便問一下 你的頭骨靈活嗎
By to the way, is your skull flexible?
- 啥  - 沒啥
- What? - Never mind.
可能沒什麼問題 別動
It will be probably okay. Hold still.
哇哦
Wow!
還剩30秒就玩完啦
30 seconds to doom.
我應該輸入我的密碼 密碼是
I shall input my password. It is...
" 我的名字是哎呀 斯邁克船長很偉大而且
"My name is Oh and Captain Smek is great and
任何人都不會想到的是1
anyone who does not think that is a poomp 1."
我想知道為什麼沒人會猜到
I wonder why no one guessed that.
我也不知道
I do not know.
- 不管用嗎  - 不可能
- It didn't work? - Impossible!
這就是密碼呀
That is password!
那是 哦 不 大寫鎖定鍵
That is-- Oh, no! Caps Lock.
快點 快點 快點
Come on, come on, come on!
派對開始啦 派對開始啦
Come party. Come party. Come party. Come party.
Come party. Come party.
成功了
Yes!
Duang 起作用了
Fa-da! It has worked.
起作用了
It worked!
你成功了 哎呀
You did it, Oh!
太驚險了
That was closeness.
站起來
On your feet.
你還是要去找我媽媽
You still have to find my mom.
這很簡單 我們現在應該找
That is simplicity. We shall now searching on...
露絲·圖琪
Lucy Tucci.
" 露西·圖琪 "
"Lucy Tucci."
澳大利亞
Australia.
找到邁瑪
Observe Mimom.
這不好笑
That's not funny.
這不是你的邁瑪嗎
This is not your mimom?
你在開玩笑嗎
Are you kidding?
這不是她
That's not her!
你確定
Sure?
我知道 我知道 好嗎
I know, I know. Okay?
你已經說了兩周了
You've been saying that for two weeks.
求你了
Please!
她有著灰色的大眼睛和美麗的棕色頭髮
She has big green eyes and beautiful brown skin.
媽媽
Mom.
所以告訴我她在哪兒
So tell me where she is.
或者給我找一個知道她在哪兒的波波來
Or find me a Boov who can.
求你了
Please.
你看起來就像小一號的邁瑪
Gratuity Tucci looks just like tiny Mimom.
格拉托依蒂·圖琪 為什麼
Gratuity Tucci? Whyfor--
謝謝你 謝謝你
Thank you! Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you!
我不敢相信 我媽媽在澳大利亞
I can't believe it! My mom's in Australia!
而且我取消了我的邀請
And I has cancelled my e-vite!
我終於可以不用再藏著了
I can finally come out of the hiding.
太棒了
Yes!
哈 哈 哈
Well, well, well.
哈嘍
Hello?
拿著我的皇冠
Hold my crown.
一定要非常小心 這是唯一的一個
And be very careful. It's the only one.
哈 哈 哈
Well, well, well.
你真的以為你能逃得掉嗎
Did you really think you could escape?
逃走 不 不 不
Escape? No, no, no.
你看 我只是過來告訴你
You see, I was just coming to tell you--
儘管你精心偽裝
Despite your elaborate disguise...
電腦已經認出你是
the computer recognized you as...
逃犯波波
the fugitive Boov!
但是他現在是英雄波波
But he's a hero Boov now!
是的 我改正了我的錯誤
Yes! I has fixed my mistake!
是的 但是在此之前 你犯了錯
Yes, but before that, you has made your mistake.
很多錯誤
And many mistakes before that.
- 等一下 我沒有  - 很多 很多 很多 很多
- Wait, I have not-- - Many, many, many, many!
事實上
Actually--
在此之前有很多錯誤
Many mistakes before that.
- 所以 我還是要把你消滅  - 為什麼
- So, I still has to erase you. - Why?
你不能保證你不會再次犯錯
You cannot guarantee you would not make a mistake again.
- 但是我不會  - 但是你可能會
- But I would not. - But you might.
但是我不會
But I would not.
我們可以一直這麼說下去 再來一次
We could go round and round. Let's do it again!
- 但是我不會  - 但是你可能會
- But I would not. - But you might.
- 但是我不會  - 我喜歡這樣
- But I would not. - I love this!
- 但是我不會  - 現在沒勁了
- But I would not! - Bored now.
- 但是我不會  - 噓
- But I would-- - Shush!
消滅他
Erase him!
放下泡泡槍
Drop the bubble guns!
否則 我就會用這個
Or I will mess with this...
有引力的東西造成混亂
gravity thingy.
她在虛張聲勢
She is bluffing.
她不可能夠到那個
She could not possibly reach the gravity thingy.
詛咒你和你的腳趾頭
Curse you and your tippy-toe tallness!
但是沒關係
But no problem.
波波的技術太複雜
Boov technology is far too complicated for
人類小女孩不可能弄明白
simple humansgirl to figure out.
是嗎
Excuse me?
這個人類女孩可是幾何學拿到優等的
This humansgirl got an "A" in geometry.
她破解出來啦! 逃命哪!
She figured it out! Run for my life!
別擋道! 我是船長!
Out of my way! I am captain!
抓緊!
Grab on!
不! 我抓不住你啦!
Oh, no! I can't hold you!
你像是有千磅重!
You weigh, like, a thousand pounds!
鬆手吧
Let go.
- 什麼  - 相信我
- What? - Trust me.
抱歉 我的職責是先逃跑
Sorry. It is my duty to run away first.
呼
Poomp.
- 你還在等什麼  - 我不能碰
- What are you waiting for? - I cannot touch.
我操作它 它是不會有反應的
It will not work if I drive it.
好吧 我來開
Fine. I'll drive.
好痛
Owpain.
你開車技術好爛
You are terrible driver.
來吧
Come on.
來吧 來吧
Come on. Come on.
(餐前語)祝你胃口好
Bon appetit.
不 你不能了
Oh, no, you don't!
我是不會付錢的
I am not paying for that.
快動起來 你這匹蠢馬!
Come on, you stupid horse!
唔 太帥了...
Whoo, that was cl--
這次我抓住你了...
This time I got you...
你跑不掉了
and you cannot escape.
檢測到逃亡的波波
Fugitive Boov detected.
我不是
I was wrong.
跳!
Jump!
不!
Oh, no!
看 我找到我們的車了
Look! I has found our car.
豬豬!
Pig!
我不明白你為什麼要帶上這個
I do not know whyfor you brought that.
我們車裏已經有食物了
We already hads food in the car.
這不是食物 這是藝術品
It's not food, it's art.
那它不是好的藝術品
Then it is bad.
星星不是那樣子的
Stars do not look like that.
藝術品的價值不在於它看起來的樣子
It's not about how they look.
而在於它帶給你的感覺
It's about how they feel.
它們讓我感覺很熱
They feel hot.
好了 數學天才 要多久我們能到澳大利亞
Okay, math whiz, how long till we get to Australia?
17.9348個小時
17.9348 hours.
然後 格拉托依蒂·圖琪
And then, Gratuity Tucci...
就能見到邁瑪了
will see Mimom.
你聽到了嗎 豬豬
You hear that, Pig?
我等不及要告訴媽媽我真的來過巴黎了
I can't wait to tell Mom I actually went to Paris...
你知道的 她一直都想來巴黎
which you know she always wanted to do.
也許我們可以一起回到這兒
Maybe we could both come back here.
我們現在真的有一輛飛車了
We do have a flying car now.
你會怎麼用法語說"貓咪"
How do you say "cat" in French?
我想是"恰特"
I think it's "chat."
你的表情是什麼意思
What is the purpose of your face?
我困惑了
I has confusion.
我不想被消除
I do not wish to be erased.
但是也許斯邁克船長是對的
But maybe Captain Smek is right.
我很可能會繼續犯逗比錯誤
It is possible I will continue making hilarious mistakes.
可能哦
Probably.
這沒有讓我感到好受些
That is not making me feel better.
人無完人
Nobody's perfect.
我媽媽說 人只有犯過錯誤才能成長
My mom says your mistakes are what make you human.
但並沒有說波波是犯過錯誤才能成長
That is not what makes you Boov.
格拉托依蒂·圖琪...
Gratuity Tucci...
在我們來地球前
before we came...
斯邁克船長告訴我們人類需要我們
Captain Smek telled us that the humans needed us.
人類就像動物...
That the humans were just like the animals...
我們可以把人類馴化得更好...
and that we could to make them better...
教化他們
teach to them.
我們被告知人類很簡單 很落後
We were told the humans were simple and backwards.
我們原來就是這麼想的
It is what we thought.
但是我現在覺得...
But I am thinking now...
我們之前想錯了
that we were thinking wrong.
斯邁克船長是錯得最離譜的
And that Captain Smek is the wrongest.
我在想 波波一族從來就不應該來斯邁剋星球
I am thinking the Boov should never have come to Smekland.
就是地球
To Earthland.
所以 我向你道歉...
So I am saying the sorry to you...
格拉托依蒂·圖琪
Gratuity Tucci.
叫我小蒂
Call me Tip.
這是一個全新的家 陌生的國家
It was a new home, a new country.
我努力在學校裏交朋友...
I tried to make friends at school...
但是我是從巴巴多斯來的書獃子
but I was this nerd from Barbados.
但是你拿到了幾何學優等
But you dids to get an "A" in geometry.
是的 我拿到了
Yeah, I did.
我知道當其他波波說"哦哦"的時候...
I know when the other Boovs said "Oh"...
他們不願意看到我
they were not happy to see me.
事實上是 在波波中 我並不合群
The true is, among Boov, I do not fit in.
我格格不入
I fit out.
她特別了不起
She is so amazing.
她把一切家當都存了起來
She saved up everything she had...
所以我們就能搬家 搬家後也能生活得不錯
so we could move and things would be better for us.
我等不及想見到邁瑪啦
I cannot wait to meet Mimom.
"我是斯邁克船長 噓 噓 噓"
"My name is Captain Smek. Shush, shush, shush."
"波波族的技術對於簡單的人類女孩來說
"Boov technology is far too complicated
太複雜了 你是不可能破解的"
for simple humansgirl to figure out."
他們是怎麼找到我們的
How did they find us?
我不知道!
I do not know!
等等 他們沒有攻擊我們
Wait. They're not attacking.
因為他們在逃跑
Because they are running away.
他們為什麼逃跑
Why are they running away?
只可能有一個原因
There can only be one reason.
格爾族
Gorg.
這說不通 我阻止了那條信息
This makes no sense. I stopped the message.
格爾族不可能找到我們
Gorg cannot to finding us.
那為什麼他們找到了
Then how did they?
肯定有其他原因
There must be some other reason!
哦! 在我們後面!
Oh, behind us!
啟動作戰系統
Engage weapons system.
我們有作戰系統?
We have a weapons system?
發射玉米煎餅魚雷
Go, Burrito Torpedo!
命中!
Yes!
我們被擊中了 我們的葡萄汁在流失
We've been hit! We're losing Grape Escape!
橘子汁也在洩漏
We lost Tangerine Twist!
如果我們沒有巴斯塔酸橙汁 我就不能操控了
If we lose Busta Lime, I cannot control!
按按鈕出票 我們要墜車啦
Click and ticket. We are to crash!
噢!
Oh!
不 不 不
No, no, no.
雪泥! 不要!
Slushious! No!
不要光站那兒看著! 幫忙啊!
Don't just stand there! Help!
拜託 拜託 拜託
Come on, come on, come on!
雪泥! 不要!
Slushious! No!
她壞掉了
She's gone.
我們死定了
We are doomed.
現在我再也去不了澳大利亞了
Now I'll never make it to Australia.
我要開始唱波波滅亡曲了
I will now sing the Boov Death Song.
格爾族戰船!
A Gorg ship!
打斷滅亡曲是很粗魯的
It is rude to interrupt the Death Song.
也許你可以從那艘船上取下部分來修我們的車
Maybe you could take the parts from it to fix our car.
我不能夠 那些是格爾族的東西
I cannot. Those are Gorg parts.
它們規格不一樣的
They are metric.
我們不能夠功虧一簣
We're not getting this close and giving up.
- 快點  - 不要!
- Come on. - No!
跑得越遠越危險
Always with the running towards danger.
別再做悲觀的懦夫波波了
Stop being such a Boov.
這是我們唯一的機會 快點
It's our only chance. Come on.
這是不會成功的!
This has low probability of success!
- 走吧  - 等等
- Let's go. - Wait!
等什麼
For what?
等你改變心意
For you to change your mind.
走吧
Come on.
沒有飛行員
There's no pilot.
這只是一艘無人駕駛飛船
It is just a drone.
本來我們會完蛋的
That could have been badness.
但是我們現在也不能掉以輕心
But we are not safety.
格爾族的航母很快就會到這兒了
Gorg mothership will be here soon enough.
有用的上的嗎
Can you use any of this?
壞的
Broken.
沒用
Useless.
可能會導致熱核裂變
Likely to cause thermonuclear fission.
這是什麼
What is it?
這是格爾族的超級芯片
It is Gorg super-chip!
它為什麼叫超級芯片
Why is it called a super-chip?
它大部分是在市場上流通
It is mostly marketing.
但它是使得格爾族
But it is key...
擁有更強更好機器的關鍵物品
for the Gorg are having machines that are stronger and better at everything.
因此我們永遠不能夠和格爾族平等對戰
So we can never fight them with equaltude.
我們能用這個修飛船嗎
Can we use it to fix Slushious?
可以的 飛船一定可以修好的
Yes, yes! The Slushious will fly again.
太棒啦
Yes!
真是事半功倍啊
It was low probability of success.
你真是個厲害的波波
Some Boov you are.
快點
Quickly.
我們得快點修好飛船找到邁瑪
We must fix the Slushious and find Mimom.
是我媽啦
"My" mom.
我不就是這個意思嗎
That is the thing I said.
我就知道這能行的
I knew this would all work out!
你太厲害啦
You were awesome!
你一定能找到我媽的
We're gonna find my mom...
你會成為一個大英雄並且給大家瞅瞅這塊超級芯片
you're gonna show everybody the super-chip and be a big hero
甚至連斯邁克船長都要
and even Captain Smek will have to--
好多人啊
That's a lot of people.
- 再見了 波波 - 趕緊走吧
- Bye, Boov! - Get lost!
天哪 你們的跑路技能點挺厲害的
Wow. You guys really are good at running away.
是的
Yes.
我們很擅長
Yes, we are.
看那裏
Look, over there!
我就是在那裏看到我媽媽的
That's where we saw my mom!
快點 這是最後一艘船了
Hurry up, it is the last ship!
沒事啦 豬豬 我會和媽媽一起回來的
It's okay, Pig. I'll be back with Mom.
我們 快到了
We're almost there!
這邊
Over here.
- 什麼 - 快點
- What? - Hurry!
我就不懂了 她在裏面嗎
I don't understand. She's in there?
是的
Yes.
趕緊把真相吐出來
Tell me the truth.
沒時間了
There is no time.
你可以跟我一起走
You can come with me.
你會很安全的
You will be safety.
我媽不在那艘船上 是不是
My mom's not on that ship, is she?
你答應我幫我找她的 現在你卻要走了
You promised to help me find her, and you're leaving?
- 你這個大騙子 - 不要啊
- You lied to me. - No!
欺騙是件壞事
A lie is a bad thing.
我干了壞事這樣你才能活下來
I did a thing so you can live.
我媽在這 我不走
I'm not going. My mom is here.
你永遠不會找到她的
You will never find her.
百分百你找不到的
It is 100%.
坐以待斃不會帶來任何希望的
Staying now does not make hope.
格爾族的母艦快來了
Gorg mothership will be here soon.
它會毀滅這個星球的
It destroys planets.
- 我們現在必須跑路了 - 不
- We must run away now! - No!
這是真的
It is true.
人類竟然連這點小事都不能理解
Humanspersons cannot even understand simple, simple things.
我在救你啊 我是你的夥伴
I am saving you! I am being your friend.
不 你只是在逃跑
No, you're just running away.
你離不開你的家族
You don't leave your family.
你不能理解我
But you can't understand that
因為你只是只波波
because you're just a Boov!
你從來就沒跟我在一個陣營
You've never been my friend.
等等
Wait!
最後逃離口開始檢票
Final escape pod departing.
我一直很討厭格爾族啊 他們總是能找到我們
I hate upon the Gorg! They are always finding us!
格爾族的母艦
The Gorg mothership!
我們完蛋了
We are doomed!
快跑
Run away!
讓我先走 我抱著孩子呢
Make a path, I'm holding a baby.
他是那只逃跑的波波
It is the fugitive Boov!
他怎麼反方向跑
He is running towards the danger!
快阻止他
Stop him!
不要啊
Undo!
船長 我們達到了史上最快速
Captain, we are achieving new highest speeds!
你都做了些啥喲 這是啥
What has you done? What is that thing?
格爾族的超級芯片
It is Gorg super-chip.
啥
What?
格爾族無人機撞壞了
Gorg drone crashed
我遇到了 結果就找到芯片
and I ran to it and I found the chip.
夠了
Enough.
你遇上過格爾族
You ran to a Gorg?
他不懼險阻
He runs towards the danger?
他是個怎樣的波波啊
What kind of Boov is he?
超級波波
He is like a Super Boov.
不不不
No, no, no.
他才不是超級波波呢
He is not a Super Boov.
在艦上只有一隻超級波波
There is only one Super Boov on this ship,
你們都知道是誰
and you know who it is.
近在眼前哦
You're looking at him.
我組織的大逃亡
I invented running away.
看看這個 我的噓噓棒
And look at this. I have the Shusher.
我才是船長
I am your captain.
但你不是個合格的船長
But you are not good captain.
啥
What?
你告訴我們的 我們都信了
You telled us these things, and we all believed them.
起碼我信了
I believed them.
但我遇到了個人類
But then I met a humansperson.
她不像你所說的那樣
And she is not like you said.
她很勇敢 聰慧
She is brave and smart...
很關心其他人類
and cares about other humanspersons.
我們波波甚至不互相關心
In a way that we Boov do not even care about each other.
她甚至很關心我
She even cares about me.
雖然我幾乎啥也沒做
And I've done very little to earn that.
波波族雖然在很多方面很強
The Boov may be superior in many ways.
對
Yeah.
但不是在我現在認為重要的方面厲害
but not in the ways that I now thinks are most important.
哦 天
Big deal!
我聽夠了 閉嘴吧你
I have had enough. Shush!
你才真的是夠了
That is enough shushing.
你膽夠肥敢讓我閉嘴
How dare you shush a shushing!
哎呀是正確的我們需要一個新的船長
Oh is right. We need a new captain.
我覺得應該讓小歐來當
I thinks it should be Oh!
我 不
Me? No.
不 他才配不上船長之職
No! He cannot be captain.
我有噓噓棒 我是船長
I have the Shusher. I am captain!
再也不是了
Not anymore!
他不會知道怎麼控制這個的
He will not know how to operate it!
很複雜的
It is very complicated.
一頭中 一頭輕
Heavy on one end, light on the other.
安靜
Shush!
棒
Booyah!
不 我不適合領導波波
No, I am not a Leader Boov.
我做過太多錯事了
I makes far too many mistakes.
你不是唯一一個犯錯誤的波波
You are not the only Boov who makes mistakes.
比如
For examples
我的過失是沒當你的好夥伴
my mistake is not being your friend.
小歐船長萬歲
All hail Captain Oh!
我看到是你幹的了
I saw who did that!
我有仇必報 你看著辦吧
I hold grudges, you know!
小歐 你是最棒的
Oh, you're the best!
想讓我辦個派對嗎 小歐
Want me to host party, Oh?
走開
Go away.
才不呢 你應該說 是誰呀
No, you are supposed to be saying "Who is there?"
我就能說
Then I am to be saying
哞
"Moo!"
小歐
Oh!
我簡直不敢相信
I can't believe it!
但我看著你們的船離開的呀
But I saw your ship leave!
你回來了 你還回來幹啥
But you came back! What are you doing here?
這裏是我心之所屬
It is where I belongs.
你和豬豬是我的朋友
You and Pigcat are my friends.
並且
And alsos, too
我給過你承諾
I gave you a promise.
他是我朋友
He's my friend.
謝謝你
Thank you.
媽媽
Mom.
小蒂蒂 你真是我的寶貝
Tippy. My beautiful girl.
媽媽 我每個地方都找遍了
I've been looking everywhere, Mom.
我超怕 我再也見不到你了
I was so scared we'd never see each other again.
媽媽 我不會放棄找你的
Mom, I never would have stopped looking until I found you.
他們仍然在找
They are still looking.
格爾族不是侵略者
Gorg are not the takers.
波波族才是
Boov are.
我們必須證明我們的猜測
We must demonstrate our affections later.
但現在還有個問題
There is still one problem.
不好意思 那是什麼
Excuse me, what is that?
格爾族的母艦
That is Gorg mothership.
它是來毀滅這個星球的
It is here to destroy the planet.
它要毀滅這個星球
It's going to destroy the planet?
對 我有個計劃
Yes. But I haves a plan.
小歐
Oh?
你在幹嘛
What are you doing?
我很抱歉
I am sorry.
小蒂現在不准出來
Tip cannot come into the out now.
我要彌補自己犯下的錯
I am fixing my mistake.
小歐 你一個人做不到的
Oh! You can't do this on your own!
也許做不到
Maybe not.
但我心存希望
But I haves hope.
不
No!
停下 別去
Stop, no!
別一個人干啊
Please don't do this by yourself!
別啊 不要去
No! Don't!
Oh!
快停下
Stop!
看吶
Look!
喂
Hey!
格爾
Gorg!
大叫根本沒用
It is useless to yell.
格爾
Gorg!
他們看不見他
They're not gonna see him.
這樣沒用
It's not gonna work!
聖誕快樂
Merry Christmas.
- 現在  - 快拆開
- Now? - Just open it.
謝謝 甜心 可現在
Thank you, sweetheart, but what--
你在幹嘛
What are you doing?
讓駕駛者分心
Distracting the driver.
奏效了 母艦停下了
It worked! The ship's stopping!
可是沒法及時得停下來
It's not gonna stop in time!
快停下啊
Stop faster!
他一定要快點離開那兒
He's gotta get out of there!
媽媽 幫我搞定這東西
Mom, help me with this thing!
小歐
Oh!
快跑
Run!
小蒂
Tip!
快停下
Stop!
小蒂
Tip!
媽媽
Mom!
小歐
Oh!
你還活著
You're alive.
你把我嚇壞了
But you scared me so bad!
你嚇壞了
You were scared?
我至少還是第三名
I almost made a number three.
不算太難
Not too hard!
還是有點可能性的
It is still a possibility.
那是在說什麼呀
What was all that?
不是所有的格爾語都能對應成人類語言
Not all Gorg-speak has humans words.
可事實上 他們並不是我邀請來的
But, it turns out, Gorg was not here because of my invitation...
雖然他們很樂意接受邀請
though Gorg would have been happy to attend.
他們在這兒是因為 他們正追蹤這塊石頭
Gorg was here because Gorg was tracking the rock.
這裏面有什麼
What was in that thing?
格爾族系
Gorg family.
他們的整個新生代
It is entire next generation.
整個嗎
All of them?
整個
All of them.
難怪他們一直追著你們
No wonder they've been chasing you.
不是他們 是他
Not "they," "he."
顯然 那個格爾人是最後一個格爾族人了
Apparently, that Gorg is last Gorg.
這就是為什麼這塊石頭那麼重要
That is why rock was so important.
沒有它 他就會孤獨一人
Without it, he was alonely...
然後獨自滅絕
and would someday be extinctly...
格爾一族也將煙消雲散
which made Gorg cranky and irrational...
永遠湮滅在宇宙中
and physically violent.
他就像個人類女孩
He was just like humansgirl.
他傷心的快發瘋了
He was sad-mad.
謝謝你
Thanking you.
謝謝你 漂亮擊掌
Thanking you! High hand touching.
哈哈 來吧 二連擊
Yeah, give it here. High hand touching.
再高點 你太慢啦
Up high! You are too slow.
漂亮擊掌 這下好疼
High hand touching! That hurt.
豬豬貓
Pigcat!
嗨 小歐
Hey, Oh!
你好啊 好友凱爾
Hello, friend Kyle.
我也有一樣的顏色
I have that same color.
- 嗨 邁媽  - 嗨 小歐
- Hi, Mimom. - Hi, Oh.
派對太贊啦
Awesome party, Oh!
有人參加的排隊實在是太帶感啦
Parties are so much more fun when other people show up.
是時候再進一步了吧
Is it time to pick it up a level?
對
Yes!
這下要變得更帶勁啦
This is gonna be sweet!
一起來手舞足蹈吧
Drop it like it has a high temperature!
哎呀 不好
Oh, no!
控制不住我的身體啦
What is happening to my body?
波波們搖擺起來
Shake your Boov thang!
把你的雙手舉在空中 舞步跳的很輕鬆
My hands are in the air like I just do not care!
我有了新家 新夥伴 新的開端
I has a new start in a new home with new friends.
現在 每一天都是最棒的一天
And now, every day is best day ever!
你們都受邀參加派對 派對 派對
You are all invited to a party, party, party.
來銀河系 在北斗星的地方右拐
Just head to the Milky Way. Turn right at the Big Dipper.
太陽系第三行星
Third planet from the Sun.
來看我的氣球
Look for my balloons!
來派對吧
Come party!
大伙們 茄子
Everybody, smile!